http://www.macdermid.com/privacy-policy

This website uses cookies to give you the best browsing experience possible and to better understand
how you use the MacDermid site. By clicking the Accept and close button
you consent to the use of cookies. If you do not wish to have cookies enabled please see our Privacy
policy to learn how to disable your cookies. Accept
Quality SystemsSustainabilitySix SigmaSeveso InformationMacDermid Alpha Electronics SolutionsMacDermid Enthone Industrial SolutionsMacDermid Graphics SolutionsMacDermid Offshore Solutions
MACDERMID
MACDERMID ALPHAELECTRONICS SOLUTIONSChemicals Serving the Electronics Industry
MACDERMID ENTHONE INDUSTRIAL SOLUTIONSSurface Finishing Specialty Chemicals
MACDERMID GRAPHICS SOLUTIONSPrinting Industry Consumables
MACDERMID OFFSHORE SOLUTIONSProduction & Drilling Control Fluids
PrivacyPolicy
EU PRIVACY Notice concerning customer and other business-related personal data
Version dated 9 May 2018
Effective Date: 25 May 2018
1. INFORMATION ABOUT US
2. CONTACT DETAILS
3. WHAT PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT AND WHY?
4. Sharing OF YOUR INFORMATION
5. Transfers outside the European Economic Area (EEA)
6. YOUR RIGHTS
1. INFORMATION ABOUT US AND INTRODUCTION
Platform Specialty Products Corporation (sometimes referred to as “Platform,” “we,” the “Company,” or “us”) values and protects the Personal Data of our existing and prospective customers, business partners, suppliers, and website visitors.  Platform is a global, diversified producer of high technology specialty chemical products and provider of technical services with headquarters in the United States and trading in several countries some of which within the European Union.
This Privacy Notice covering personal data of individuals in the EU contains important information about the way in which we collect, use, disclose, retain and otherwise process personal data.
For the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 and any implementing legislation (the "GDPR"), Platform Specialty Products Corporation is the data controller responsible for any personal data that we process.
Executive Headquarters:
Platform Specialty Products Corporation
1450 Centrepark Boulevard, Suite 210
West Palm Beach, Florida 33401
561-207-9600
Platform Specialty Products have appointed MacDermid Graphics Solutions Europe as our representative office in the European Union.
2. CONTACT DETAILS
Questions, comments, and other communications regarding this Privacy Notice, or our privacy practices in general, are welcomed and should be addressed to our Data Protection Privacy Advocate. Any queries and requests regarding this privacy notice may be sent by email or post to:
Data Protection Privacy Advocate
MacDermid Graphics Solutions Europe
Rue de l’Industrie- BP 30160- 68702 Cernay Cedex, France
Email:  DPPA@MacDermid.com
3. WHAT PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT AND WHY?
This section 3 covers the different sources and categories of personal data that we collect and process, why we do so, and the lawful bases for processing by Platform.
Depending on your relationship with Platform, please see the relevant section below where we describe how we obtain your personal data and how we will treat it.
This privacy notice covers the processing of information for the following categories of individuals:
Section 3.1            Representatives of our Existing or Prospective Customers, Business Partners and Vendors
Section 3.2            Visitors to Premises
Section 3.3            Website Visitors
Section 3.4            Job applicants
3.1 Representatives of our Existing or Prospective Customers, Business Partners and Vendors
We may collect personal data related to employees, directors, authorised signatories, in other words, representatives of Platform’s existing or prospective customers, business partners or vendors.
A - Sources of personal data
B - Personal data that we collect and process
C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?
D – How long do we keep your personal data?
A - Sources of personal data
We may obtain your personal data from the following sources:
a)      from you directly,
b)      from a company that employs you, if you are an employee of our existing or prospective customer, business partner or vendor,
c)      from Platform’s affiliates see the list in Annex 1;
d)      during networking events that we have either hosted, or sponsored, or attended; and/or
e)      from publicly available sources (for example, your company website or social media sites)
B - Personal data that we collect and process
We may collect the following categories of personal data relating to our existing or prospective customers’ or vendors’ employees, officers, authorised signatories, and other associated individuals:
a)              name;
b)             business address;
c)              business email address;
d)             business telephone number;
e)             job title;
f)               date of birth;
g)              business bank details;
h)             credit information; and/or
i)               billing information.
C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?
Representatives of our Existing or Prospective Customers and Vendors
We may use your personal data to:
Our lawful basis for doing so is:
Our legitimate interests in doing so are:
Provide you with our products or services or receive products or services from you
Legitimate Interest
Efficiently fulfil our contractual and legal obligations
Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)
Establish and manage our relationship
Efficiently fulfil our contractual and legal obligations
Account Management
Understand the market in which we operate
Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)
Exercise or defend legal claims
Learn about how our products and services are or may be used
Understand the market in which we operate
Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)
Security
Managing security, risk and fraud prevention
Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)
Let you know about our products, services and events that may be of interest to you by letter, telephone, email or other forms of electronic communication
Promote our goods and services
Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)
If you object to us using your personal data for these purposes, including direct marketing, please let us know using the email address provided in section 2.
Where we use your email to communicate marketing information to you we will seek your prior consent where required to do so by law.
D – How long do we keep your personal data?
We will keep and Process your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected. We will keep your personal data for the duration of our business relationship with regard to the provision of goods or services to you.  We will retain information about you after the closure of a customer account or the end of a business relationship as long as required for legal, regulatory and legitimate business purposes. Upon expiry of such data retention period, we will delete it securely.
3.2 Visitors to Our Premises
A - Sources of personal data
B - Personal data that we collect and process
C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?
D – How long do we keep your personal data?
A - Sources of personal data
We may obtain your personal data from you directly and from our business systems’ records.
B - Personal data that we collect and process
a)      name;
b)      business contact details;
c)      organisation;
d)      role;
e)      time and date of your visit; and/or
f)       image (for example, from CCTV cameras at our premises).
C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?
Visitors to our Premises
We may use your personal data to:
Our lawful basis for doing so is:
Our legitimate interests in doing so are:
Security
Legitimate Interest
Managing security, risk and crime prevention
Maintain records of visitors to our premises
Management Reporting
We may use your personal data to:
Our lawful basis for doing so is:
Where you provide us with information regarding your disability, we will process it as part of our legal obligation to make reasonable adjustments for recruitment process
Legal Obligation
If you object to us using your contact details for these purposes, please let us know using the email address provided in section 2.
D – How long do we keep your personal data?
We keep your personal data for as long as necessary to ensure security of our office visitors, once this period ends and when there is no longer a legal or a business need to keep it, we will delete it securely.
3.3 Website Visitors
A - Sources of personal data
B - Personal data that we collect and process
C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?
A - Sources of personal data
We may obtain your personal data from the following sources:
a)      from you directly (for example, at the time of subscribing to any services offered on our website, including but not limited to ‘Contact Us’ submissions on our website macdermid.com, email mailing lists, interactive services, posting material or requesting further goods or services);
b)      from your device or browser; and/or
c)      if you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
B - Personal data that we collect and process
a)      name;
b)      username;
c)      email address
d)      operating system;
e)      browser type;
f)       cookie data (please refer to the below links to configure cookies);
g)      preferences regarding online marketing; and/or
h)      IP address.
Configuring Browser Cookies
Mozilla FireFox
Microsoft Internet Explorer
Google Chrome
Apple Safari
Opera
C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?
Website Visitors
We may use your personal data to:
Our lawful basis for doing so is:
Our legitimate interests in doing so are:
Provide our website services to you
Legitimate Interest
Website Management
Promote our goods and services
Account Management
Establish and manage our relationship
Understand the market in which we operate
Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)
Account Management
Learn about our websites(s) users’ browsing patterns and the performance of our website(s)
Website Management
Security
Managing security, risk and crime prevention
Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)
Let you know about our products, services and events that may be of interest to you by letter, telephone, email or other forms of electronic communication
Promote our goods and services
Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)
Learn about how our products or services may be used
Understand the market in which we operate
Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)
If you object to us using your contact details for these purposes, including direct marketing, please send us an email using the email address in section 2.
Where we use cookies or similar technologies we will seek your prior consent where required to do so by law.
Where we use your email to communicate marketing information to you we will seek your prior consent where required to do so by law.
3.4 Job Applicants
We may collect personal data related to job applicants for positions advertised on our website.
A - Sources of personal data
B - Personal data that we collect and process
C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?
D – How long do we keep your personal data?
A - Sources of personal data
We may obtain your personal data from the following sources:
a)      from you directly,
b)      from a third party, for example, individual referrals or a recruitment agency,
c)      from Platform’s affiliates [see the list in Annex 1];
d)      via hard copy and web-based application forms;
e)      during networking events that we have either hosted, or sponsored, or attended; and/or
f)       from publicly available sources (for example, professional networks, such as LinkedIn)
B - Personal data that we collect and process
We may collect the following categories of personal data, which may differ, depending on the content of your CV or baseline documents you submit to us:
a)             name;
b)             residence address;
c)              personal email address;
d)             telephone number;
e)             date of birth;
f)               career and education history;
g)              skills, experience, and qualifications;
h)             personal interests, languages spoken, questionnaire results;
i)               gender;
j)              names and contact details for references. Please note that it is your responsibility to obtain consent from your references prior to providing us personal information about them;
k)             current and historic salary details together with salary expectations;
l)               details of your current benefit entitlements;
m)           information about your entitlement to work in the country in which the Platform EU affiliate is located;
C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?
Job Applicants
We may use your personal data to:
Our lawful basis for doing so is:
Contact referees
Conduct background checks
Verify information submitted
Consider you for other employment positions with Platform’s
Consent
Check your eligibility to work in the country in which the Platform’s affiliate is located
Legal obligation
Where you provide us with information regarding your disability, we will process it as part of our legal obligation to make reasonable adjustments for recruitment process
We may use your personal data to:
Our lawful basis for doing so is:
Our legitimate interests in doing so are:
Facilitate the selection process
Assess and confirm your suitability for employment
Communicate with you
Legitimate interests
Talent Management (including at an intra-group level)
Execute business process and internal management
Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)
Safeguard the security of our infrastructure, premises, assets and office equipment, including prevention of criminal activity, defending legal claims
Managing security, risk and crime prevention
Exercise or defend legal claims
If you object to us using your personal data for these purposes, including direct marketing, please let us know using the email address provided in section 2.
D – How long do we keep your personal data?
We will keep and Process your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected. If you are successful and we hire you, we will keep your CV as part of your employee record for the duration of your employment with us. We will keep CVs and documents submitted by unsuccessful candidates for no longer than six months after decision, unless we obtained their consent to keep it for longer.
4. SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION
Data that we collect may be shared with our affiliated companies, suppliers or service providers, and government authorities. See details in relevant sections below.
Affiliates
Government or regulatory bodies
Service providers
Mergers and acquisitions
Affiliates
We may share your personal data with affiliates (see the list in Annex 1 below) for the following purposes:
-       to provide us with IT support and systems and tools for managing operations,
-       overall group-wide risk management,
-       litigation management,
-       compliance with regulatory requirements applicable to affiliates, and
-       marketing.
In so doing, our affiliates may be data controllers and / or data processors of your personal data together Platform.  As data controllers and / or data processors, these affiliates will process your data in line with the intra-group data transfer agreements in line with the requirements of the GDPR.
Government or regulatory authorities
We may also disclose information about you if we have a legal duty to do so or if we are required or requested by any governmental or regulatory authority or similar body pursuant to any applicable law or regulation. Otherwise, we will keep information about you confidential.
Service providers
We may give information about you to organisations that provide a service to us or are acting as our agents, subject to contractual measures that we put in place obligating such organisations, on the understanding that they will keep the information confidential and will comply with applicable data protection laws.
For example, we may share your information with the following types of service providers that we engage with:
a)     Technical support providers who assist with our website and IT infrastructure;
b)    Third party software providers, who may include ‘software as a service’ solution providers, where the provider hosts the relevant personal data on our behalf;
c)     Professional advisers such as solicitors, accountants, tax advisors, auditors and insurance brokers;
d)    Money laundering and compliance search providers;
e)    Providers that help us store, collate and organise information effectively and securely, both electronically and in hard copy format, and for marketing purposes; and/or
f)      Providers that help us generate and collate reviews in relation to our services.
Mergers and acquisitions
In the context of mergers and acquisitions, we may transfer your personal data to potential purchasers and their advisors, subject to appropriate confidentiality obligations, in the event we decide to dispose of all or parts of its business.
5.TRANSFERS OUTSIDE THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA (EEA)
In general, when transferring your personal data outside the EEA (which consists of EU member states and Iceland, Lichtenstein and Norway), we will only do so using one of the following safeguards:
(a)            the transfer is to a non-EEA country which has an adequacy decision by the EU Commission (e.g. Israel);
(b)            the transfer is covered by a contractual agreement, which covers the GDPR requirements relating to transfers to countries outside the EEA.
(c)            the transfer is to an organization which has Binding Corporate Rules approved by an EU data protection authority; or
(d)            the transfer is to an organization in the US that is EU-US Privacy Shield certified.
You may request a copy of the relevant document by contacting us as indicated  in section 2 above.
6. YOUR RIGHTS
You have the following rights in relation to your personal data under the GDPR:
a)     to obtain information on how we handle your personal data and access documents which contain your personal data;
b)    to request us to correct or update your personal data if it is inaccurate or out of date;
i.         to object to the processing of your personal data for the purposes of our legitimate interests, as discussed above;
c)     to erase personal data about you that is held by us:
i.         which is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which is was collected,
ii.         to the processing of which you object, or
iii.         which may have been unlawfully processed by us;
d)    to restrict processing by us, i.e. to restrict processing to storage only:
i.         where you oppose to deletion of your personal data and prefer restriction of processing instead, or
ii.         where you object to the processing by us on the basis of its legitimate interests;
e)    to transmit personal data that you submitted to us back to you or to another organisation in certain circumstances; and
f)      If we rely on your consent (for example, when setting cookies on your device or for direct marketing or for keeping your CV), you may withdraw your consent at any time.
If you at any time decide to exercise any of these rights, please contact us as indicated in section 2 above.
If you are unhappy with how we have dealt with your request or concern, you have the right to file a complaint with a data protection supervisory authority in the EU.
Annex 1 – List of Affiliates
Show
PLATFORM SPECIALTY PRODUCTS CORPORATION
Subsidiaries
The following are subsidiaries of Platform Specialty Products Corporation as of December 31, 2017 and the state or jurisdictions in which they are incorporated or organized:
Subsidiaries
State or Jurisdiction of Incorporation/Organization
Afgri Crop (Pty) Ltd
Malawi
Agrifocus Limitada
Mozambique
Agriphar de Colombia SAS
Colombia
Agriphar Poland Sp z.o.o.
AI Divestitures, Inc.
Delaware
Alent Alpha Metals (Shanghai) Co., Ltd (we plan to liquidate)
China
Alent Alpha Metals (Shenzhen) Co., Ltd.
China
Alent Enthone Chemistry (Shanghai) Co., Ltd.
China
Alent Enthone Chemistry Trading (Shanghai) Co., Ltd.
China
Alent Finance Company (Ireland 1)
Ireland
Alent Finance Company (Ireland 2)
Alent Inc.
Rhodes Island
Alent Investments Inc.
Alent USA Holding Inc.
Alpha Assembly Solutions, Inc.
Delaware
Alpha Assembly Solutions Korea Ltd
Korea
Alpha Assembly Solutions Netherlands B.V.
Alpha Assembly Solutions (Shanghai) Trading Co., Ltd.
Alpha Metals Mexico S.A. de C.V.
Mexico
Alpha Metals Trading Mexico S.A. de C.V.
Anion Quimica Industrial S.A.
Brazil
Aprochim SpA
Italy
AR Mexican Holdings Inc.
Arysta LifeScience Adria, trgovina s kemicnimi proizvodi d.o.o.
Arysta LifeScience Australia Pty Ltd.
Arysta LifeScience do Brasil Industria Quimica e Agropecuaria SA
Arysta LifeScience Hellas S.A./Plant Protection, Nutrition and Other Related Products and Services
Arysta LifeScience Inc.
Arysta LifeScience Netherlands B.V.
Autotype Holdings (USA), Inc.
Illinois
Bayport Chemical Service Inc.
Compugraphics International Ltd.
United Kingdom
Compugraphics Jena GmbH
Germany
Compugraphics USA Inc.
Cookson Pigments Inc.
Echo International Inc.
Delaware
EI Liquidation Inc.
Enthone B.V.
Netherlands
Enthone Iberica S.A.
Enthone Sp. Z.o.o.
Poland
Enthone-OMI (Hong Kong) Co. Ltd.
MacDermid Acumen Inc.
MacDermid Americas Acquisitions Inc.
Delaware
MacDermid Anion Inc.
Delaware
MacDermid Autotype Inc.
MacDermid Brazil Inc.
MacDermid Chemical Industries Argentina Inc.
Delaware
MacDermid Continental Investments Ltd.
MacDermid Enthone de Mexico S.A. de C.V.
Mexico
MacDermid Enthone Inc.
Delaware
MacDermid Enthone Electronics Solutions (M) Sdn. Bhd.
MacDermid Enthone Sp. Z.o.o.
Poland
MacDermid Enthone Taiwan Co., Ltd.
Taiwan
MacDermid Enthone Technology (Suzhou) Co., Ltd.
China
MacDermid Enthone Trading Shanghai Co. Ltd.
China
MacDermid Enthone Singapore Pte Ltd.
MacDermid Group Inc.
MacDermid Houston Inc.
MacDermid Investment Corp.
MacDermid Mexico Holdings S de RL de CV (we are liquidating)
MacDermid Operations S de RL de CV (we are liquidating)
Mexico
MacDermid Overseas Asia Ltd
Delaware
MacDermid (Panyu) Specialty Chemicals Co., Ltd.
MacDermid Performance Solutions Canada Inc.
MacDermid Performance Solutions Hong Kong Ltd.
Hong Kong
MacDermid Performance Solutions Japan K.K.
Japan
MacDermid Performance Solutions Korea Inc.
Korea
MacDermid Performance Solutions Kimyasal Sanayi ve Ticaret A.S.
Turkey
MacDermid Performance Solutions Mexico Services, S.A. de C.V.
Mexico
MacDermid Performance Solutions Singapore Pte Ltd.
MacDermid Services S de RL de CV (we are liquidating)
Mexico
MacDermid Singapore Pte Ltd
Singapore
MacDermid South America Inc.
Delaware
MacDermid South Atlantic Inc.
Delaware
MacDermid Shenzhen Trading Co., Ltd.
China
MacDermid Suisse Sarl.
Switzerland
MacDermid Taiwan Holdings B.V.
Netherlands
MacDermid Technology (Suzhou) Co., Ltd
China
MacDermid Texas Inc.
M & P Compounding Inc.
Napp Printing Plate Distribution Inc.
PTI Produtos Tecnicos Para Impessao LtdMacdermid Graphics Solutions Ltda
SPC Divestiture Inc.
Delaware
Specialty Polymers Inc.
Volcano Agrociencia Industria e Comercio de Defensivos Agricolas Ltda
W. Canning Inc.
Delaware
W. Canning International B.V.
MacDermid Performance Solutions UK Limited - Section 172(1) Statement
© Copyright MacDermid, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Site Design and Hosting by WORX.
